When the world turns upside down, the trick is coming out on top.
King of the Hill is a drama, history film directed by Steven Soderbergh.
Based on the Depression-era bildungsroman memoir of writer A.
Hotchner, the film follows the story of a boy struggling
to survive on his own in a hotel in St.
Louis after his mother is committed to a sanatorium with tuberculosis.
His father, a German immigrant and traveling salesman working for the Hamilton Watch
Company, is off on long trips from which the boy cannot be certain he will return.
Aaron Kurlander, played by Jesse Bradford.
Mr. Kurlander, played by Jeroen Krabbé.
Mrs. Kurlander, played by Lisa Eichhorn.
Miss Mathey, played by Karen Allen.
Mr. Mungo, played by Spalding Gray.
Lydia, played by Elizabeth McGovern.
King of the Hill is a 1993 American coming-of-age drama film
written and directed by Steven Soderbergh.
Adapted from A.
Hotchner's Depression-era memoir, the film follows a young boy navigating life alone in a
hotel after his mother is hospitalized and his father is oftentimes absent.
It stars Jesse Bradford as Aaron, alongside Jeroen
Krabbé and Lisa Eichhorn as his parents.
The cast also includes Spalding Gray, Adrien Brody, Karen
Allen and Lauryn Hill in supporting roles.
The film received universal critical acclaim for its
storytelling and rich character development.
It marked the second time Soderbergh directed from his own screenplay, following
his 1989 Academy Award–nominated film Sex, Lies, and Videotape.
King of the Hill was nominated for the Palme d'Or at the Cannes Film Festival, and was
named one of the top ten films of 1993 by Time and Entertainment Weekly.
In 2024, British GQ ranked it as the best film of Soderbergh's career.
It was released on Blu-ray by The Criterion Collection.
The film explores themes of hotel, great depression, canary,
based on memoir or autobiography, tuberculosis.
The tone is emotional.